Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ beauthescientist (LinkedIn) beauwalker.com (Personal) methoddatascience.com (Company)

Top Skills

Statistics

R

Data Analysis

Languages

Spanish (Professional Working)
English (Native or Bilingual)
Russian (Full Professional)

Honors-Awards

Dean's Scholarship Recipient

Publications

Field and lab soil measurements for determining threshold friction velocity across deserts in the southwestern U.S.

Law Firm Social Media Platform Adoption in Orange County, CA

The Interaction of Aeolian and Fluvial Processes in Dry Washes on the Colorado Plateau, USA

Controls on sediment production in two deserts

Aeolian and Fluvial Losses of Sediment On The Colorado Plateau

Patents

METHODS FOR INCREASING MODEL ACCURACY IN REDUCED TIME

SYSTEMS AND METHODS FOR DETERMINING ATTRIBUTES OF BIOLOGICAL SAMPLES

Beau Walker

Chief Data Scientist. Consultant. Inventor.

Orange County, California Area

Summary

I make companies faster, more efficient, and smarter with data science, machine learning, and AI.

I'm a consulting data scientist and inventor. I help individuals and companies become data science rock stars - to use data science to transform the way that they think, make decisions, and build products.

I have years of experience both doing and teaching data science. I'm a generalist: my experience includes AI / machine learning, business analytics, data collection, data engineering and architecture, software development, study design, data preparation, experimental design, algorithm and model development, reporting, data visualization, and custom intellectual property development (I've invented a number of custom proprietary machine learning algorithms).

I believe that great data scientists don't just use the best methods, they build products that can have a lasting impact on the business after they are gone.

My consulting philosophy focuses on:

- data science education and training;
- data science infrastructure;
- data driven ROI; and
- R&D and intellectual property development.

Contact Me

I've hit the limit of 30,000 connections and LinkedIn won't let me accept additional invites. Please follow me (+Follow below) and check out www.methoddatascience.com.

- > methoddatascience.com
- > beau@methoddatascience.com
- > www.github.com/incredibeau
- > instagram.com/beauthescientist

Experience

Method Data Science Founder; Chief Data Scientist April 2018 - Present (2 years) Orange County, California Area

We're a full-service data science dev shop with deep experience in multiple industries including sales and marketing, finance, banking, software, legal, retail and ecommerce, biotech, and pharma.

We specialize in automation, machine learning / AI, reporting, custom web apps, and APIs.

Example projects include customer lifetime value and cohort analysis, disease prediction, asset classification, stock market prediction, fashion image classification. We develop solutions using machine learning and AI, NLP, clustering and unsupervised learning, report automation, custom web app, dashboard, and API development.

Learn more at www.methoddatascience.com

PRESTON VENTURES

Senior Data Scientist January 2018 - January 2020 (2 years 1 month) Aliso Viejo, California

Preston Ventures manages multi-billion-dollar mortality-based investment assets for some of the world's largest private equity and hedge funds.

During my time at Preston I've:

- > Architected and built data science pipeline from scratch, which involved moving from a piecemeal Excel-based framework to an R, Python, SQL, and machine learning focus;
- > Improved internal efficiency, report generation, and turn-around time for various processes 10-4000x;

Invented 15+ novel patentable analytic and machine learning methods which led to a 3-10x increase in accuracy of models (inventions include cutting-edge methods in survival analysis, feature selection, matching algorithms); and
 Directed narrative, advocacy, and adoption of data science to executive team and clients.

UC Irvine

Instructor - Data Boot Camp (UCI Continuing Education) December 2017 - May 2018 (6 months)

Irvine, California

The Data Analytics Bootcamp at UC Irvine is a 6-month comprehensive data analytics and data science bootcamp managed by Trilogy Education.

During my time at UC Irvine I:

- > Managed class of 30 students and two teaching assistants;
- > Developed and taught course content in Python, SQL, noSQL, APIs, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, R, Tableau, Spark, Machine Learning, Data Analytics, and Data Visualization; and
- > Mentored new data scientists and provided project and career advice.

Liquid Biosciences Senior Data Scientist March 2017 - January 2018 (11 months)

Aliso Viejo, California

Liquid Biosciences is a custom healthcare machine learning firm for large pharmaceutical and healthcare clients.

While at Liquid I:

- > Managed data science team and interfaced with software engineers;
- > Developed data science pipeline (sales support, data pre-processing; modeling; data visualization);
- > Developed novel methods for processing million+ row 'omics, clinical, and payer claims datasets;
- > Performed modeling with evolutionary programming and genetic algorithm techniques; and
- > Invented or co-invented 50+ patent applications and trade secrets which contributed to funding round raise of hundreds of thousands of dollars.

Beau Walker // Marketing Scientist
Consulting Data Scientist
January 2010 - January 2018 (8 years 1 month)
Irvine, CA

Consulting / freelance / contract data scientist and marketing consultant.

Projects include:

- > Al / artificial intelligence consulting
- > deep learning classifiers
- > IoT device sensor dashboards (data as a product).
- > NLP classification of retail products data (coded bot behind hagglekat.com)
- > keyword and social media analysis of law firm websites
- > social media influencer analytics (Instagram, Facebook, Twitter APIs)
- > survey analysis
- > web and marketing analytics
- > machine learning

Learn more at www.beauwalker.com and www.hagglestats.com

Fish IP Law LLP Associate JD May 2014 - March 2017 (2 years 11 months)

Fish IP Law was formerly Fish & Tsang LLP. I worked as an IP clerk, marketing director, and associate JD.

Legal:

Irvine

- > Assisted attorneys with procurement of IP rights (patent, trademark, copyright, trade secret), and with enforcement of IP rights in Federal District Court and USPTO proceedings.
- > Experienced with litigation, licensing, patent drafting, office actions, and trademark applications.

Marketing & Data Science:

- > Handled all aspects of the firm's marketing, including PR, social media, networking events, and lead generation and tracking.
- > Some of the things I accomplished while managing the marketing team at F&T include:
- development and launch of a legal reference app for iOS and Android
- · development and launch of sub-brands and associated websites
- successful campaign for partner's bid for the OCBA Board of Directors
- development of new firm website

- · comprehensive reporting and lead tracking
- 75% increase in new clients from online sources

Brigham Young University 5 years 4 months

Graduate Research Assistant
May 2011 - November 2014 (3 years 7 months)

Provo, Utah Area

- > MS thesis involved developing in-depth methods for Computer Vision / Short-Range Photogrammetry in ecological settings using Matlab, Agisoft Photoscan, Python, and UNIX on BYU's super computer.
- > Performed advanced data mining and analysis on a variety of complex multivariable datasets in R.
- > Performed data collection and analysis with LiCor 6400, RTK GPS, Decagon soil and weather sensors.
- > Coded an agent-based computer model of grazing, climate, and vegetation interactions in NetLogo.

Research Assistant

January 2010 - August 2013 (3 years 8 months)

- > Designed and implemented field and lab experiments and observational studies across a variety of projects ranging from plant physiology and chemistry, ecosystem services, remote sensing, and soil chemistry.
- > Managed 2-5 person field and lab crews and trained undergrads on field and lab techniques.
- > Analyzed and reported our results in lab meetings, journal articles, and national conferences.

www.gilllab.byu.edu

Teaching Assistant

August 2009 - April 2012 (2 years 9 months)

Provo, Utah Area

- > Developed curriculum and assignments for Biology 100 course with professor.
- > Managed a team of 2-6 other teaching assistants and coordinated grading and tutoring efforts.
- > Taught weekly classes, led discussions and review sessions, and provided one-on-one tutoring for students.

Writing Fellow

August 2009 - May 2010 (10 months)

As a Writing Fellow, I was a writing tutor for Bioethics and Geology classes. I worked with faculty and students of class-specific writing assignments. I provided one-on-one feedback, focusing specifically on long-term writing development.

818 Group
Data Scientist
May 2012 - August 2013 (1 year 4 months)
Provo, Utah

- > Coordinated 100k+ row marketing and web analytics datasets for multiple clients ranging from small consumer products businesses, to large international corporations in the service industry.
- > Programmed and automated detailed marketing reports in R, SQL, and XML. I led data mining efforts and analysis in R and MS SQL Server.
- > Provided in-depth analysis on new data, complex web analytics, and key support and feedback on A/B campaign testing.
- > Performed testing and provided feedback of marketing product development. I developed an automated reporting interface with in R and SQL (using a Shiny app).
- > Performed NLP and LSI text mining analysis of newsletter campaigns.
- > Coordinated with software developers on feature development for our Aquifor Product suite (marketing automation platform).
- > Researched and developed RainBoost product suite, a content marketing / SEO solution.

USGS

Biological Technician May 2011 - August 2011 (4 months) Moab, Utah

- > Based at the Canyonlands Research Station in Moab, UT.
- > Coordinated permit and research design with 3 different BLM field offices.
- > Performed an in depth desert survey that set the foundation for future research.
- > Trained USGS and BYU crews on GPS RTK survey techniques.

JyzeFit
Social Media Manager and Web Developer
January 2008 - August 2009 (1 year 8 months)
Provo, Utah Area

Exercise product startup (www.onepoundgym.com)

- > Developed and designed the website and ad campaigns, and managed social media strategy.
- > Sold product at tradeshows and fairs.

Brigham Young University Research Assistant August 2007 - May 2008 (10 months)

Provo, Utah Area

- > Drafted and reviewed geologic figures for the 3rd Edition of "Geologic History Of Utah: A Guide To Utah's Rocks" Hintze and Kowallis (2009).
- > Co-authored "A Field Guide To Rock Canyon," an educational pamphlet, with Dean Bart J. Kowallis.

Education

UC Irvine

JD, Intellectual Property Law · (2013 - 2016)

Brigham Young University

MS, Ecology and Evolutionary Biology · (2011 - 2014)

Brigham Young University

BS, Biology · (2004 - 2011)